# LENA **KREMIN**

lenavkrem@gmail.com · (616) 334-6035 · linkedin.com/in/lena-kremin

I am an experienced researcher with 9+ years in the fields of user research, psychology, and linguistics. I use a range of research methods and analyses to answer questions about how people think and behave.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### MAY 2022 - PRESENT

# **UX RESEARCHER, USERZOOM**

- Design and conduct end-to-end remote usability studies, competitive benchmarks, and heuristic evaluations, assessing designs and user behaviors
- Analyze and present data, translating research findings into actionable insights and narratives
- Consult with clients on their research goals and long-term research roadmap, identifying high priority research topics

#### 2018 - 2022

# **DOCTORAL RESEARCHER**, CONCORDIA UNIVERSITY

- Designed 5 independent, overlapping end-to-end research studies, advancing knowledge in the fields of language development and bilingualism
- Analyzed and visualized data on user responses for 4 projects, interpreting and contextualizing research results
- Mentored junior researchers, providing guidance throughout the research process to maintain a high standard of work
- Published 2 articles in international journals and presented at 9 regional and international conferences, disseminating research findings among a multi-disciplinary audience

#### 2020 - 2021

# **COURSE INSTRUCTOR**, CONCORDIA UNIVERSITY

- Collaborated with 3 instructors and 2 teaching assistants across academic ranks, negotiating expectations and delegating tasks
- Evaluated course content, adapting materials to clearly communicate information on research methods and design principles to 75 students from various backgrounds (student rating on clarity of communication: 4.3/5)
- Pivoted course to a virtual format during the COVID-19 pandemic, solving problems as they arose to maintain efficient and quality instruction (student rating on being an overall effective teacher: 4.75/5)

#### 2017 - 2018

# LAB MANAGER, PENN STATE UNIVERSITY

- Developed a productive environment for a cross-functional team of 5 lead investigators, 4 research assistants, and participants, facilitating industry-leading research and analysis
- Organized weekly research presentations, ensuring clear communication between multiple stakeholders and university departments

# **SKILLS**

#### **RESEARCH METHODS**

- Eye tracking
- Interviews
- Surveys
- Usability studies
- Remote and in-person studies
- A/B testing

# **STATISTICS**

- Descriptive and inferential statistics
- Correlation
- Linear and logistic mixed modeling
- Pupillometry
- Data visualization

# SOFTWARE & PROGRAMMING

- R (intermediate)
- SPSS (basic)
- SQL (basic)

# **EDUCATION**

2022

#### PHD IN PSYCHOLOGY

CONCORDIA UNIVERSITY GPA: 4.0

#### 2017

#### MA IN LINGUISTICS

UTRECHT UNIVERSITY GPA: 4.0

# 2015

# BA IN PSYCHOLOGY & LINGUISTICS

UNIVERSITY OF MICHIGAN GPA: 3.9